{"tossups": [{"question": "Quakers and Anglicans fought over this state\u2019s governorship in Cary\u2019s Rebellion. This modern-day state was home to the Albemarle Settlements, and its Halifax Resolves were the first official resolution calling for American independence. This state and a southern neighbor were granted to Robert Heath as Cape Fear in 1629. The Battle of Guilford Court House took place in, for ten points, what Mid-Atlantic state with capital at Raleigh?", "answer": "<b> North Carolina</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "After putting down Quintus Cassius Longinus\u2019s rebellion in Spain, this man received a triumph and was Master of the Horse twice under Julius Caesar. This man, who served as the last pontifex maximus of the Roman Republic after Caesar\u2019s death, was overthrown after trying to claim Sicily after the final defeat of Sextus Pompey, setting the stage for the final showdown between Antony and Octavian. For ten points, name this third member of the Second Triumvirate.", "answer": "Marcus Aemilius<b> Lepidus</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "The technology behind these objects was revolutionized by the use of crystals that oscillate at a frequency of two to the 15th power hertz, leading to the so-called \u201cQuartz Crisis\u201d for slow-adapting competitors of Seiko and Citizen. New York City\u2019s Canal Street is home to counterfeit vendors of, for ten points, what personal timepieces produced by Rolex?", "answer": "<b> watch</b>es (do not prompt on clocks)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Misc Arts"}, {"question": "In a speech at Boston\u2019s Home Market Club, this man noted that the U.S. needs to \u201cput an end to false economics which lure humanity to utter chaos\u201d in a speech that opens by blaming a \u201cfever [that] has rendered men irrational.\u201d This man argued that \u201cAmerica\u2019s present need is not heroics, but healing; not nostrums, but\u201d the slogan of his presidential campaign, in which he beat Leonard Wood on the tenth ballot at the nominating convention and beat James Cox in the election. For ten points, name this US president who promised a \u201cReturn to Normalcy\u201d after World War I.", "answer": "Warren Gamaliel<b> Harding</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "During this man\u2019s reign, the Lingqu Canal was built as part of a system connecting the Yangtze and Pearl Rivers. This man survived an assassination attempt in which a heavy metal cone was dropped on his carriage from atop a mountain. This man, who was advised by chancellor Li Si to make Legalism the official ideology, targeted the Hundred Schools of Thought by burning Confucian books and buried their scholars alive. The Terracotta Army was commissioned by, for ten points, what first emperor of a unified China?", "answer": "Qin<b> Shi Huang</b>di (accept<b> Ying</b> Zheng; accept<b> Zhao</b> Zheng; accept<b> King Zheng</b> of Qin)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "79 bottle of orange juice. During an event in this city referred to as Sa-I-Gu, Richard Rhee and 20 of his employees set up an armed camp to defend the California Market. For ten points, name this city where racial tensions between the Korean and Black communities exploded after four police officers were acquitted for the beating of Rodney King.", "answer": "<b> Los Angeles</b> (accept<b> LA</b>)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "A black-and-white photo of a 1913 rally is juxtaposed with a photo of this event that was digitally altered by the National Archives for an exhibit celebrating the centennial of the 19th Amendment; the alterations included blurring part of the phrase \u201cGod hates Trump.\u201d Vanessa Wruble co-led this event, whose attendance dwarfed that of a ceremony held the previous day. For ten points, name this January 21, 2017 rally, the largest single-day protest in American history, against the policies of Donald Trump.", "answer": "2017<b> Women\u2019s March</b> (accept 2017<b> Women\u2019s March</b> on Washington; accept descriptive answers that include the words<b> Women\u2019s March</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "A member of this family calmed an angry crowd at the execution of George Burroughs by claiming that he was \u201cno ordained minister.\u201d The work<em> Remarkable Provinces</em>, which contains selections from the controversial<em> Malleus Maleficarum</em>, was written by a member of this family. During a 1692 event, a member of this family warned John Richards against the use of spectral evidence. The Salem Witch Trials involved, for ten points, what powerful Puritan family that included Increase and Cotton?", "answer": "<b> Mather</b> family (accept Cotton<b> Mather</b>; accept<b> Increase</b> Mather after \u201cRemarkable\u201d is read)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "These people were able to place a poster on a monarch\u2019s bedchamber door at Amboise [am-BWAHZ] in the Affair of the Placards. These people, who attempted to settle Fort Caroline, were massacred two days after an attack on one of them, Gaspard de Coligny. Catherine de Medici probably ordered the St. Bartholomew\u2019s Day Massacre against these people, the subjects of Louis XIV\u2019s Edict of Fontainebleau and Henry IV\u2019s Edict of Nantes. For ten points, name this group of French Calvinists.", "answer": "<b> Huguenot</b>s (prompt on French Protestants/Calvinists before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This monarch offered refuge to the exiled Duke of Warwick and arranged an alliance between the Duke and Margaret of Anjou. In the Treaty of Picquigny, this ruler paid 75,000 crowns to end the Hundred Years\u2019 War. The League of the Public Weal was organized by the Duke of Berry to oppose this monarch. The death of this king\u2019s rival, Charles the Bold, allowed him to annex Burgundy. For ten points, name this French king from 1461 to 1483 whose nickname is derived from his webs of schemes.", "answer": "<b> Louis XI</b> [11] (accept<b> Louis</b> the Universal<b> Spider</b>; prompt on Louis)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "A \u201cLittle\u201d version of this event was presided over by W.G. Boshoff and saw one target say \u201cMy Lord, I am a professional agitator.\u201d Percy Yutar was the chief prosecutor during this event, in which one side was defended by Bram Fischer. A defendant in this trial claimed that the Sharpeville Massacre justified the use of force by the oppressed in a three-hour-long speech given by a man who declared \u201cI am prepared to die.\u201d For ten points, name this trial in which Nelson Mandela was sentenced to life imprisonment in 1964.", "answer": "<b> Rivonia</b> Trial", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "A player of this instrument collaborated on the album<em> East Meets West</em> with Yehudi Menuhin at the 1966 Bath Music Festival. Vilayat Khan popularized this instrument, which was played by a virtuoso at the charity<em> Concert for Bangla Desh</em> and taught to George Harrison for songs like \u201cNorwegian Wood.\u201dThe score for Satyajit Ray\u2019s<em> Apu</em> Trilogy was composed by Ravi Shankar, a master of, for ten points, what Hindustani string instrument?", "answer": "<b> sitar</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "Hong Kong censored<em> Killing Commendatore</em>, the most recent novel by, for ten points, what Japanese novelist of <em>1Q84</em> and<em> The Wind Up Bird Chronicle</em>?", "answer": "Haruki<b> Murakami</b>", "metadata": "Literature - World Literature - Misc Literature"}, {}, {"question": "Harry von Arnim saw this man as a rival and thus stole sensitive records from an embassy in France. This man, whose policies included a Sickness Insurance Law and Accident Insurance Law, formed the League of the Three Emperors. This man helped provoke France into war with the Ems Dispatch and launched the Kulturkampf against Catholic power. This user of<em> Realpolitik</em> gave the \u201ciron and blood\u201dspeech to the Prussian Chamber of Deputies. For ten points, name this first Chancellor of a unified Germany.", "answer": "Otto von<b> Bismarck</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>In 1851, gold was discovered in this state\u2019s town of Ophir. The last autocratic governor of this state, Lachlan Macquarie, constructed the inland city of Bathurst after the crossing of the Blue Mountains. Years after surviving the (+) Mutiny on the Bounty, Vice-Admiral William Bligh was made governor of this state; he faced the (*)</b> Rum Rebellion here. In 1788, Arthur Phillip landed the First Fleet near Botany Bay in what is now, for ten points, what Australian state south of Queensland, where James Cook charted what is now Sydney?", "answer": "<b> New South Wales</b> (accept<b> NSW</b>; do not prompt on \u201cWales\u201d)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>In December 1945, this man was sent on a mission to China to unify the Nationalists and Communists; his negotiations lasted over a year before failing. Joseph Stalin ordered Poland and (+) Czechoslovakia to refuse aid from an initiative named for this man. In 1953, this US Army officer was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize, in large part for his work on the European (*)</b> Recovery Program after World War II. For ten points, name this American diplomat who served as Secretary of State and Defense under Harry Truman and orchestrated aid for Western Europe in a namesake plan.", "answer": "George<b> Marshall</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>This composer\u2019s patriotic works include</b><em><b> Carillon</b></em><b>, a recitation for speaker and orchestra in honor of Belgium during World War I. An oratorio by this man was composed for the</b> <b>Birmingham Music Festival and is based on a Cardinal (+)</b> <b>Newman poem. Jacqueline du</b> <b>Pre made her 1962 concert debut performing this composer\u2019s Cello Concerto in E minor. A march by this composer of</b><em><b> The</b></em><b> (*) </b> <em>Dream of Gerontius</em> served as the recessional for the marriage of Prince Charles and Princess Diana. For ten points, name this English composer of the<em> Pomp and</em> <em>Circumstance</em> marches.", "answer": "Sir Edward William<b> Elgar</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {}, {}], "bonuses": []}